#### **University of Waterloo**

### **Co-operative Work Terms**

## Waleed Rizwan 20680917

# 3B Accounting and Financial Management, Honours, Co-operative Program Computing Minor

Work Term	Employer	Evaluation
Jan - Apr 2019	Office of the Auditor General of Ontario	SATISFACTORY
	Office of the Legislative Assembly	
	Toronto Ontario Canada	
	Auditor (Trainee Program)	
Sep - Dec 2019	Toronto Hydro Corporation	EXCELLENT
	Head Office	
	Toronto Ontario Canada	
	Senior Technical Student	
Sep - Dec 2020	Loblaw Companies Limited	EXCELLENT
·	Corporate	
	BRAMPTON Ontario Canada	
	Application Developer	

Planned Future Work Term(s)

Sep - Dec 2021

To Whom It May Concern,

I am a fourth-year **Finance** student at the **University of Waterloo**. After reading your job posting I am sure that my combined skill set in **programming** and **finance** would help bring value to the team.

To quickly summarize my **programming** abilities, I am a capable web developer utilizing the **React JavaScript** framework to build clean and responsive UIs. I can also manage backend tasks using tools like the **Python** web framework **Flask** to create an **API** to serve multiple functions. Some other frameworks/tools I have experience in using for web development are **Material UI**, **Redux**, **Bootstrap**, and **Firebase**. My **Python** skills are versatile beyond web development and can be applied to multiple areas. I have used them for purposes such as **option pricing** and **sentiment analysis** to analyze the emotions of Tweets.

Through my coursework, I have developed an advanced knowledge of accounting and finance. For example, I can create and analyze **financial statements** and apply different valuation techniques such as **discounted cash flow analysis** for public companies and **leveraged buyout models** for **private equity**.

All of my skills have come from project-based learning and not just reading or watching tutorials. Examples of my work can be found on my portfolio website **WaleedsCode.com** and my **GitHub** which is linked **here.** 

Thank you for taking the time to review my application. I look forward to the opportunity of speaking with you to discuss my qualifications further and the nature of the position you have available.

Sincerely,

Waleed Rizwan

## Waleed Rizwan

w2rizwan@gmail.com | WaleedsCode.com | github.com/waleedrizwan

#### **Education**

**University of Waterloo** 

Waterloo, ON

Bachelor of Accounting & Financial Management, Co-op

September 2017 - Present

- Deans Honors List (2017 Present)
- Minor in Computer Science

#### **Experience**

**University of Waterloo** 

Waterloo, ON

Teaching Assistant - Global Financial Markets

January 2021 - April 2021

- Assessed and provided feedback on 900+ midterms and final examinations
- Co-Hosted a midterm exam review session with 200+ attendees
- Managed a Piazza discussion board with 400+ students

**Loblaw Companies Ltd.** 

Brampton, ON

**Application Developer** 

September 2020 - December 2020

- Developed a new inventory control website using Appian to be used by all 27 distribution centers in Canada
- Reduced time spent on non-value adding tasks such as data retrieval, and manual clerical work by 50%
- Improved user experience by implementing a French translation feature to translate the website content and store user's language preference in Oracle backend
- Resolved over 30 user reported bugs, and confirmed with users
- Led weekly meetings with warehouse managers to assist in migration from legacy software to new platform

Toronto Hydro Toronto, ON

Senior Technical Student

September 2019 - December 2019

- · Coordinated daily trade settlement with energy suppliers to verify expenses for finance team
- Used Excel VBA to calculate total charges per day using hourly electricity prices and actual usage data
- Preprocessed monthly invoices worth hundreds of millions of dollars to confirm accurate totals

**Auditor General of Ontario** 

Toronto, ON

• Evaluated the financial responsibility of Ontario hospitals through the 2019 Patient Safety Audit

- Interviewed board executives, and medical staff from sampled hospitals to gain insight into common issues
- Collected and organized Health Quality inspection reports from every hospital in Ontario to gauge performance

#### **University of Waterloo, Living Learning Community**

Waterloo, ON

Peer Leader

Auditor

January 2020 - April 2020

January 2019 - April 2019

• Served as a source of academic and personal support to 500+ first year School of Accounting and Finance students living on campus to help with transition to university life

#### **Projects**

**Portfolio Partner** 

PortfolioPartner.ca

- Built a free portfolio notification service for Canadian investors with 50+ registered users
- · Saved users time through daily SMS notifications of portfolio performance updates
- Implemented automated price watching feature to notify users when stocks reach a given price

#### **Investment Analysis Tool**

github.com/waleedrizwan/portfolioanalysistool

- Created a Python script which lets users analyze a mock portfolio of stocks
- Automatically calculates historic and expected future return, market risk, and volatility of the portfolio

#### Skills, Activities & Interests

Programming/Tools: Python, JavaScript, SQL, Excel VBA, Tableau, Adobe Photoshop

Activities: Fall 2018 Orientation Leader, 2016 Halton Region Habitat for Humanity Volunteer

Interests: Portrait Photography, Web Design and Programming

# UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO UNOFFICIAL GRADE REPORT

#### Waleed Rizwan 20680917

3B Accounting and Financial Management, Honours, Co-operative Program Computing Minor

Spring 2021				
BET 10 CS 20 CS 23 ECON 23 AFM 43	24 00 00 31 31 33	Wealth Management Foundations of Entre Practice Concept for Adv Computer U Algorithmic Problem Solving Intro to International Econ Business Strategy		
Term Average: Fall 2020	N/A	Decision:		
	3	Co-operative Work Term		CR
	3	Communication		CR
Term Average:	N/A	Decision:		
Spring 2020				
AFM 32 AFM 34 AFM 37	11 22 44 77 16 80.4	Connections to Ethical Conte Derivative Securities Intro to Business Analytics Priv Equity and Venture Cap Intro to Computer Science 2 Decision:	ext Good standing	78 76 86 81 81
Winter 2020			· ·	
HRM 20 AFM 33	91 00 73 35 88.67	Intermed Financial Account 2 Basic Human Resources Mg Cases & Apps in Corp Finance Designing Functional Program Decision:	mt ce	CR 97 82 87
Fall 2019				
	2 5 N/A	Co-operative Work Term Project Management Decision:		CR CR
Spring 2019				
AFM 24 AFM 27 AFM 28	11 41 74 30 31 76.2	Connections to Bus Context Intro Business Information Managerial Finance 2 Intro to Org Behaviour Business Law Decision:	Good standing	75 81 74 75 76
Winter 2019				
	2 1 N/A	Reflection and Learning Co-operative Work Term Decision:		CR CR
Fall 2018				
AFM 20 AFM 27 AFM 29	1 02 04 73 91 09 73.25	Career Fundamentals Intro to Public Practice Intro to Applied Finance Managerial Finance 1 Intermed Financial Account 1 Intro to Academic Writing Decision:	Excellent standing	CR WD 80 60 74 79

١٨	/i	n	te	r	2	n	1	Q
	, ,				_	u	•	U

AFM	102		Intro to Managerial Acct	86
AFM	121		Intro to Global Financial Mkts	84
ECON	102		Intro to Macroeconomics	87
SPCOM	111		Leadership & Communication	87
STAT	211		Intro Stat & Sampling Acc	68
Term A	verage:	82.4	Decision: Excellent standing	
Fall 2017	•			
AFM	101		Intro to Financial Accounting	84
AFM	131		Intro to Business in N.A.	88
MATH	109		Mathematics for Accounting	91
CS	100		Intro Computing through Appl	90
ECON	101		Intro to Microeconomics	84
Term A	verage:	87.4	Decision: Excellent standing	